Finding aid to the Carole A. Oglesby papers SSC.MS.00492
Sophia Smith Collection
- Carole A. Oglesby papers, 1964-2003; Accession 2003-S-0070; 51.417 linear feet (60 containers)
  - M. Adrian et al lecture, Coleman, and scene from " The Longest Yard", 1 Cassettes Audio cassette (Box 58)
  - AM. Springfield and AM. S.C., 1 Cassettes Audio cassette (Box 58)
  - WEEP #6, Doug #3- last 45 min, Jean #8- first 15 min, July 6, 1982; 1 Cassettes Audio cassette (Box 58)
    Side A: "7/6/82 WEEP #6" Side B: "Doug #3- last 45 min / Jean #8- first 15 min / cont'd from A"
  - Taped lectures, 1 Cassettes Audio cassette (Box 58)
    Side A: "Dr. Harris - Physiological Factors Affecting the Female Athlete Penn State" Side B: "Dr. [?] - Motor Performance Characteristics [Affecting?] Female Athletes"
  - Taped lectures, 1 Cassettes Audio cassette (Box 58)
    Side A: Dr. McLeod - Bioengineer- Tech Analysis of Mechanisms of Tennis / Dr. Nirschl Side B: Dr. Kirschel - Tennis Injuries / Dr. Kulund - Motocross
  - Carole Oglesby and Milt Cole, January 29, 1975; 1 Cassettes Audio cassette (Box 58)
    Side 1: Carole Oglesby + Milt Cole Jan. 29th #1 + #2 Side 2: Oglesby + Cole + Phone Calls + Advertisements - January 29, 1975 99.3 FM Dial - Northampton, Mass
  - Valentine's Day songs, 1 Cassettes Audio cassette (Box 58)
  - Christmas message [from Carole?], 1 Cassettes Audio cassette (Box 58)
  - Taping of referee workshop, May 18, 1975; 1 Cassettes Audio cassette. Audio quality is poor, difficult to discern what event is being recorded. (Box 58)
    One side labelled: May 18th 1975 Orals Other side: K. [Jerrillion?} Official[s?]
  - Meeting recording, possibly USOC, 1 Cassettes Audio cassette. (Box 58)
    Meeting or lecture, talk about hiring, possibly related to United States Olympic Committee.
  - Oversize desk calendars, June, 1995-July, 2000; undated (Box 59)
  - Original 15"x11" Women in Sport pencil drawing by Heidi Nestor and note cards (Box 59)
  - Road Runners Club of New York "women-only mini marathon" poster and miscellaneous women sports organizations and other posters, 1975 May 10; undated (Box 59)
  - Coca Cola poster honoring women of South Africa in celebration of National Women's Day, 1997 August 9 (Box 59)
  - Oversize map tracing route of paddling trip through lakes at Minnesota-Canada border (Box 59)
  - Oversize posters, publications, calendars, Olympics publications, scrapbook and miscellaneous memorabilia (Box 60)
  - Office for Civil Rights oversize chart: Federal Laws and Regulations Prohibiting Sex Discrimination, March, 1976 (Drawer 10)
- Carole A. Oglesby papers addition, 1950-2016; Accession 2018-S-0001; 20.75 linear feet (15 record cartons, 1 flat box, 1 full size letter document box, 1 flat folder); 3 items (3 CDs); 17 items (17 VHS cassette tapes)
  This series contains information and materials from the various women's sports organizations which Oglesby was a member of, materials from courses she took and taught, from lectures and presentations, publications, media, and conference materials. It also includes personal correspondence, photographs, and other items, such as her course work both as an undergraduate and graduate student.
  One record carton of books, not by or about Oglesby, were donated to the Northampton League of Women Voters for their annual book fair.
  Videotapes; CDs
  - Email printouts (personal and miscellaneous), 1995-2013 (Box 1)
  - Beyond Sport correspondence, 2009-2014 (Box 1)
  - Women's health correspondence, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Racism and racism in sports education, 1992-1998; 2 folders (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Gender equality, 1979-1992 (Box 2)
  - Sexual harrassment, 1994-2005 (Box 2)
  - Violence Against Women conference, Los Angeles, 2007-2010; 4 folders (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - Gold sport shorts, approximately 1955-1965 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1953 (Box 3)
  - Varsity letter patches, approximately 1950-1960 (Box 3)
  - Personal cards, 1995-2005 (Box 3)
  - Medals, 1950s (Box 3)
  - Personal photos, 1994-1999; 2 folders (2 envelopes) (Box 3)
  - United Nations materials related to women in sports, 1995-2008; 14 folders (14 folders) (Box 4)
  - WomenSport International (WSI) and International Working Group on Women in Sport (IWG) papers, 1981-2014; 15 folders (15 folders) (Box 5)
  - Carole Oglesby dissertation and research, 1998; 13 folders (13 folders) (Box 6)
    Includes articles, notes, correspondence, and drafts about Carole Oglesby's doctoral dissertation from Temple University.
  - Sports psychology graduate program papers, 1995-1999; 6 folders (6 folders) (Box 6)
  - Sports psychology files, approximately 1990-2000 (Box 6)
  - N.A.S. papers and nomination communications, 2001-2002 (Box 7)
  - "Image Quest" weight program, 1991; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 7)
  - California State University, Northridge (CSUN) papers, 2004-2011; 7 folders (7 folders) (Box 7)
  - Citizen Ambassadors program, 1995 (Box 7)
  - Association for Applied Sport Psychology (AASP) papers, 2001; 7 folders (7 folders) (Box 7)
  - Various publications, 1975-2000 (Box 8)
  - "Encyclopedia of Women and Sport in America" drafts, correspondence, and notes, 1998; 3 folders (3 folders) (Box 8)
  - Presentation and lecture materials, 1995-2002; 5 folders (5 folders) (Box 8)
  - Undergraduate course work and sports psych, 1960-1977; 6 folders (6 folders) (Box 8)
  - PE classes, 1975 (Box 8)
  - UMass papers, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Internship papers, 1992 (Box 8)
  - Women's Sport Foundation (WSF) papers, 1987-2005; 4 folders (4 folders) (Box 9)
  - International Working Group on Women and Sport (IWG) papers, 1991-2014; 15 folders (15 folders) (Box 9)
  - Psychology training, 1973-1993; 16 folders (16 folders) (Box 10)
  - Email printouts, 2005-2010; 13 folders (13 folders) (Box 11)
  - Various publications and notes, 1981-2007; 4 folders (4 folders) (Box 11)
  - Soroptimist notes, published information, and conference papers, 2005-2009; 9 folders (8 folders and 1 binder) (Box 12)
  - Correspondence about WSI, conferences, task forces, Soroptimist, 1997-2001; 5 folders (5 folders) (Box 12)
  - Olympics papers, 1997-2002; 2 folders (2 folders) (Box 12)
  - American Alliance for Health, Physical Education, Recreation and Dance (AAHPERD) papers, 2012-2013 (Box 13)
  - "Women and Sport: The Long Road Up" radio program, 2016; 1 folders (Box 13)
  - Email printouts concerning lectures, 1996-2007 (Box 13)
  - UN Women and Sport, 2003-2006; 3 folders (3 folders) (Box 13)
  - Various organization papers, 1996-2016; 14 folders (14 folders) (Box 13)
  - Publications, 1970s-1990s; 2 folders (1 regular and 1 legal folder) (Box 14)
  - Temple University papers, 1995-2003; 10 folders (10 folders) (Box 14)
  - 2004 Pre-Olympics final program, AASP 2002 Conference proceedings, Ending Violence Against Women policy summit 2008, IOC World Conference on Sports Sciences 1989, AAHPERD National Convention and Exposition 1992, Innovations in Sports Psychology program and proceedings 1997, ISSP 11th World Congress of Sports Psychology 2005, IOC Conference on Women and Sport 2000, American Psychological Association 98th Annual Convention 1990, NGO CSW Forum 2013 and 2014, 16th International Symposium of Adapted Physical Activity proceedings 2007, International Society of Sport Psychology program 2001, International Women and Sport conference 2007, 1990-2014; 31 items (31 books of various sizes) (Box 15)
  - Conference materials and periodicals, 1975-1995; 40 items (40 items) (Box 16)
  - Book with articles by or reference to Carole Oglesby, approximately 1980-2010; 5 items (5 items) (Box 16)
  - Photocopies of book inscriptions and acknowledgements, 1994-2009; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 16)
  - 1995 Pan Am Games, Team USA Memories: Mar Del Plata, Argentina VHS tape (Box 17)
  - PE 531: Temple University Softball, Group Dynamic VHS tape, 1993; 1 Cassettes (Box 17)
  - PE 205: Mindset for Winning VHS tape, 1996 (Box 17)
  - Benetton Sportsystem: Sports-Talk Series VHS tape, 1994 (Box 17)
  - A Tale of "O": On Being Different VHS tape (used in C. Oglesby's Psych 181 class), 1973 (Box 17)
  - Shenyang, China trip VHS tape, 1993 (Box 17)
  - A Sporting Chance Foundation VHS tape, 1986 (Box 17)
  - Princeton VHS tapes 1-3, 1990; 3 Cassettes (Box 17)
  - WomenSport Foundation (WSF) VHS tape, approximately 1990 (Box 17)
  - The Changer: A Record of the Times VHS tape, 1991 (Box 17)
  - AAHPERD tapes 3, 51, 54, 102, and 142, approximately 1993-2003; 5 Cassettes (5 audio cassette tapes) (Box 17)
  - Association for Intercollegiate Athletics for Women (AIAW) reunion CD, 2009 (Box 17)
  - Master Planning Committee: Carole Oglesby presentation, approximately 1993-2003 (Box 17)
  - International Society of Sports Psychology 11th World Congress CD, 2005 (Box 17)
  - Oversize posters and calendar pages, 1992-2005; 18 items (18 items) (Folder 1)
- Carole A. Oglesby papers further addition, 1955-2003; Accession 2018-S-0007; 14.75 linear feet (9 record cartons, 1 flat box)
  This series contains materials related to the subject of women and sport from the 1960s to the present day. It contains information and materials from the various women's sports organizations Oglesby was a member of, materials from courses she took and taught, materials from lectures and presentations, publications, media, and conference materials. Also includes personal correspondence, photographs, and items.
  Three record cartons of material created by/related to Christine M. Shelton were added to her papers held by the Sophia Smith Collection.
  - PE class materials, 1986-1999; 18 folders (18 folders); Notes on lectures, class discussion, articles, and assignment responses for PE 630, PE 607, PE 5, PE 4, PE 205, and PE 531 (Box 1)
  - Rorschach class materials, Summer 1989; 1 folders (1 legal folder) (Box 1)
  - Purdue University materials, 1964-1968 (Box 1)
  - Various organization materials, 1983-2001 (Box 2)
    Several folders of material from WSF, NAIA, Mindset Inc., QUEST, and the US Olympic Committee
  - Association for Applied Sport Psychology (AASP) conference materials, 1986-1993 (Box 2)
  - WomenSport Foundation (WSF) papers, 1985-2003 (Box 2)
  - International Working Group on Women in Sport (IWG) meeting papers, 1998-2000; 3 folders (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - Personal items (pins, flags, plaques), 1955-1999 (Box 3)
  - "Option #7445: Sports and Society" audio film recording, approximately 1980-2000 (Box 3)
  - Sports psychology papers, 1995-2003; 8 folders (8 folders) (Box 4)
  - Psychology service procedural manual, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Various publications on women's sports, 1990-2002; 4 folders (4 folders) (Box 4)
  - Title IX materials, 1975-2002; 3 folders (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - Notes, correspondence, email printouts, 1986-2003 (Box 4)
  - Workshop notes and responses, 1985-1995 (Box 4)
  - Research on women in sport and education, 1985; 3 folders (3 folders in one) (Box 4)
  - Transcripts and vitae, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Personal papers, correspondence, travel information, work evaluations, pamphlets, 1965-2002; 9 folders 9 folders (7 regular, 2 legal) (Box 5)
  - Diplomas and awards, 1961, 1964, 1969, 1999 (Box 5)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1964-1992 (Box 5)
  - Printed photographs and negatives, 1980-2000; 8 folders (8 photo folders) (Box 5)
    photographs; Negatives
  - Photo album compiled by Carole Oglesby, 1986 (Box 5)
  - United States Olympic Committee papers, 1984-2000; 8 folders (8 folders) (Box 6)
  - Encyclopedia of Women and Sport photos and letters, 1998; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 6)
  - AAHPERD papers, 2001-2002 (Box 6)
  - National Association of Girls and Women in Sport (NAGWS) papers, April 1985 (Box 6)
  - Junior tennis conference, Oct. 19-21, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Various research and organization materials (history, sport issues, education, rowing), 1984-1998; 5 folders (5 folders) (Box 6)
  - Email printouts, 1993-2003; 13 folders (13 folders) (Box 7)
  - Notes and correspondence, 1980-2003; 5 folders (5 folders) (Box 7)
  - Various publications, 1980-2002; 4 folders (4 folders); 2 items (2 booklets) (Box 8)
  - Programs for the World University Games and Girls Clubs of America, 1985-1988; 3 folders (Two binders and one folder) (Box 8)
  - Newspaper clippings related to various sports, 1984-1996 (Box 8)
  - Temple University graduate program (HPERD), faculty, and class information, 1983-1990; 5 folders (5 folders) (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous sports-related papers: notes, presentations, pamphlets, 1983-1985; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 9)
  - Teaching conference and organization materials, 1986-2000; 7 folders (7 folders) (Box 9)
  - Scientific articles (psychology), 1966-1990; 2 folders (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - "Women's Leadership in Sports" drafts, research, correspondence, 2000 (Box 10)
  - UMass opinions of women athletes study, 1974; Study conducted by Carole Oglesby for UMass on Temple University varsity athletes (Box 10)
  - Psychology studies for class use and notes, 1993; 3 folders (3 folders) (Box 10)
  - Biological feedback, questionnaires, articles, 1975-1986; 2 folders (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - "Sporting Chance" teaching equipment by the Girls Clubs of America, Inc., 1986; Includes slides, worksheets, and an audio tape for educational purposes. (Box 10)
- Carole A. Oglesby papers addition, 1953-2018; Accession 2018-S-0078
  This accession, like previous ones, contains materials related to the subject of women and sport from the 1960s to the present day. It contains information and materials from the various women's sports organizations Oglesby was a member of, materials from courses she took and taught, materials from lectures and presentations, publications, media, and conference materials. Also includes personal correspondence, photographs, and items.
  - Junior high and high school yearbooks, 1953-1957; 5 items (5 items) (Box 1)
  - Baldwin Park (CA) High School class of 1957 reunion CD, 2007; 1 items (1 CD) (Box 1)
  - International Working Group on Women and Sports (IWG) correspondence (mostly email), 2012-2016; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Beyond Sport United correspondence (mostly email), 2012-2013; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - UNESCO charter, notes, and email correspondence, 2016; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - "Trailblazers" powerpoint presentation and photographs, 2006-2008; 1 items (1 CD) (Box 1)
  - UN Commission on the Status of Women, 2010-2014; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Women and Sports Foundation (WSF) homophobia handbook, 1994-2001; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - General Women and Sports Foundation (WSF) correspondence, 2012-2014; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Articles and reports re: homophobia in sports, 1988-1994; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Western Society for the Physical Education of College Women conference, 2014; 1 folders (1 folder) (Box 1)
  - Sexual Harassment in Women's Sports: reports, correspondence, email and publications, 1996-2006 (Box 2)
  - Report of the Social Issues and Social Policy Committee for the Association for Applied Sport Psychology (AASP) Executive Board, including email correspondence and notes, 2000-2001 (Box 2)
  - "Sports, Character and Culture" conference: correspondence, emails, pamphlets, and publications, 2001-2003 (Box 2)
  - Women's Sports Foundation: correspondence, publications, meeting minutes, and handbook, 1992-2007 (Box 2)
  - "Every Child at Risk" talk including notes and transparencies., 1990-1999 (Box 2)
  - International Working Group (IWG) World Conference on Women in Sport: correspondence, reports, notes, and conference materials, 2009-2018 (Box 3)
  - "Queering Sports Psychology" presentation: notes, power point printouts, and publications, 2010 (Box 3)
  - "Conclusions on Gender Equality in Sport" meeting: notes, emails, drafts and final report, 2014 (Box 3)
  - "Physical Education and Sport: Challenges of the Third Millennium" power point presentation printout with notes, 2014 (Box 3)
  - Association for the Advancement of Applied Sport Psychology (AAASP) newsletters, 1995-2001 (Box 3)
  - Association for the Advancement of Applied Sport Psychology (AAASP) Annual Conference program, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Various presentations: notes and transparencies, 1993-2010 (Box 3)
  - International Olympic Committee proposal, 2016-2017 (Box 3)
  - "Book chapter" (draft), 2011 (Box 3)
  - 2nd International Sport and Development Conference, 2011 (Box 3)
  - Personal correspondence: Carole Oglesby to Christine Shelton, 2017-01-29 (Box 3)
  - Women's softball: correspondence and clippings, 1966-2014 (Box 3)
  - Lecture notes, reports, and email correspondence, 2011-2012 (Box 3)
  - California State University Northridge: external review report, 2014 (Box 3)
  - UN-related brochures, notes, and reports, 1984-2013 (Box 3)
  - "Links to Leadership: Promoting Women in Sports" conference: report and other publications, 1991-1992 (Box 3)
  - Notes, articles, and background materials for various workshops, 1992-2007 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence re: sabbaticals with Temple University Office of the President, 1991-1992 (Box 4)
  - Soroptimist International Los Angeles (SILA): correspondence, presentation materials, and readings, 2011-2012 (Box 4)
  - Women's Sports Foundation: email correspondence, 2013-2018 (Box 4)
  - International Working Group (IWG) on Women and Sport: email correspondence and publications, 2017-2018 (Box 4)
  - "Material for the special issue of Sex Roles: Women and Sport I co-edited," including memorabilia and email correspondence, 1956-2014 (Box 5)
  - CD: "Ending Violence Against Women" photos, 2008; 1 items 1 CD (photos) (Box 5)
  - 3 3.5 floppies: AAASP presentations; ISSP.PPT; Olgesby resume and letter, 2003; 3 items (3 3.5 floppy disks) (Box 5)
  - 3 commercially-produced video recordings including: "The Billies: Benefiting the Women's Sports Foundation with a special performance by Sir Elton John", 2007-2011; 3 items (3 DVDs) (Box 5)
  - Women's Sports International Task Force: correspondence, emails, and reports, 2012-2014 (Box 5)
  - UN Women, Los Angeles Project on Self Defense: workshop materials, email correspondence, and notes, 2016-2017 (Box 5)
  - Women's Sports Foundation Homophobia Policy Committee: notes, faxes, and drafts, 1995 (Box 5)
  - American Association of Sports Psychology project: notes, readings, and email correspondence, 2013 (Box 5)
  - Oglesby-Snyder grant: announcement and email correspondence, 2016-2017 (Box 5)
  - Taipei Conference on Women, Youth and Sports: schedule, notes, and email correspondence, 2015 (Box 5)
  - Handouts, brochures and conference programs, 2012-2015 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous email correspondence, 2004-2018 (Box 6)
  - Photographic slides, 1976 (Box 6)
  - Video recordings, including Girl Wrestler, 2004-2011; 7 items (6 DVDs and 1 8mm film reel) (Box 6)
  - Sound recording: "Diana Nyad, Woe is the WNBA", 22 Jun. 2006; 1 items (1 audio CD) (Box 6)
  - Computer media (Word documents and photos), 2000-2008; 28 items (4 CDs (3 photos; 1 Word documents) and 24 3.5 floppy disks) (Box 6)
  - Video recordings, mostly commercial, 1991-2015; 26 linear feet (10 DVDs and 16 VHS tapes) (Box 7)
  - Memorabilia, 1956-2015 (Box 7)
  - William F. Acree: correspondence, Red Cross card, and Army cap, 1943-1944 (Box 7)
  - Photographs of Carole Olgesby and others, 2000-2008 (Box 7)
  - Newspaper articles re: Carole Olgesby, 1956 (Box 7)
  - Personal correspondence, 2004-2014 (Box 7)